# **ADHITHA DIAS**

2450 Sycamore Lane, Apt 20A, West Lafayette, IN 47906 kadhitha@purdue.edu

#### **EDUCATION**

Purdue University, IN, USA

Jan 2021 - Present

Electrical and Computer Engineering, PhD.

GPA: 4.00/4.00

University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Dec 2014 - Dec 2018

B.Sc Engineering (Hons) (Computer Science & Engineering).

GPA: 4.05/4.20

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Purdue University, IN, USA

Jan 2021 - Present

Graduate Research Assistant

· Research on optimizing sparse tensor algebra.

## Sysco LABS, Sri Lanka

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

Software Engineer

· Worked on backend development, authentication and data migration for several projects.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### GitHub Notifier

This project aims at providing real time information of events from GitHub and notify you accordingly. The project is in ready-to-deployment stage on a demo server as a cron-job. The notification engine used for real time tracking is completely based on the python implementation assembled in an Android App with firebase cloud support.

## GitHub Notifier

This project aims at providing real time information of events from GitHub and notify you accordingly. The project is in ready-to-deployment stage on a demo server as a cron-job. The notification engine used for real time tracking is completely based on the python implementation assembled in an Android App with firebase cloud support.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

LanguagesC, C++, Python, Java, C#TechnologiesMVC, HTML5, CSS, LatexToolsMikTex, Kile, NetbeansDatabasesMySql, Oracle, Sqlite, NoSqlCloud TechnologiesFirebase, AWS, Google Cloud

Version Control Github

#### ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Project 'XYZ' won Best Project under Environmental Solver category under AICTE, Government of India

Recieved Scholarship For Higher Education(She) Component Under Inspire Scheme worth INR 4,00,000

Achived A Grade in Diploma in Computer Science from IBM

Won First Prize in Zonal technical quiz Competition Organized by IIT, Mumbai.

Project 'XYZ' won Best Project under Environmental Solver category under AICTE, Government of India

Recieved Scholarship For Higher Education(She) Component Under Inspire Scheme worth INR 4,00,000

Achived A Grade in Diploma in Computer Science from IBM

Won First Prize in Zonal technical quiz Competition Organized by IIT, Mumbai.

#### **EXTRA-CIRRUCULAR**

Attended a workshop on Machine Learning and artificial intelligence from faculties of IIT Roorkee in 2019 and won zonal round for the challenge presented.

Member of the Institute of Engineers since 2017.

Completed Basic Leadership Training under Project NSS, Gujarat

Attended a workshop on Machine Learning and artificial intelligence from faculties of IIT Roorkee in 2019 and won zonal round for the challenge presented.

Member of the Institute of Engineers since 2017.

Completed Basic Leadership Training under Project NSS, Gujarat

Attended a workshop on Machine Learning and artificial intelligence from faculties of IIT Roorkee in 2019 and won zonal round for the challenge presented.

Member of the Institute of Engineers since 2017.

Completed Basic Leadership Training under Project NSS, Gujarat

#### RESEARCH PROFILE

Student President, Technology and Research, IIT Gandhinagar

Publication: ABC, IOT IEEE Transactions (Impact Factor: 9.3, Status: Published)

Student President, Technology and Research, IIT Gandhinagar

Publication: ABC, IOT IEEE Transactions (Impact Factor: 9.3, Status: Published)

Student President, Technology and Research, IIT Gandhinagar

Publication: ABC, IOT IEEE Transactions (Impact Factor: 9.3, Status: Published)